(リー)ガイ先生…。
Guy Sensei!
《カカシ : これが ガイの最後の技。
That was Guy's final move!
どうなった？》
What happened?
(マダラ)ハァ ハァ…。
ハハハッ
死ぬところだったぞ こやつめ。
I almost died, you bastard!
風前の灯火だが…
楽しませてくれた 礼だ。
Your flame is about to go out.
灰になる前に→
But in gratitude for
such a great time,
俺が殺してやる！
I'll finish you off before you turn
to ash on your own!
《求道玉を蹴るだと…》
He kicked away
my Truthseeker Orb?!
(ナルト)ゲキマユ先生…。
Bushier Brow Sensei...
ナルト…。
Naruto...
いや なんとなく前とは違うな。
You seem a little different
from before.
《オビトのヤツが…》
What did Obito do?
ああ。
Yeah...
自分でも不思議に思うってばよ。
I'm still trying
to figure it out myself.
今なら全部を変えられそうだ！
But I think I can change
everything now!
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
To Rise Up
(マダラ)点穴のチャクラが消えない。
That node's chakra hasn't gone out.
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
What did he do?
いったい何をした？
《八門の最後を
止めたとでもいうのか》
Don't tell me he stopped
the end result of the Eight Gates?!
《マダラ : 求道玉といい
触れているのに なぜ…。
He touched the Truthseeker Orb,
so how can he—?
まだ回復が完全ではないからか。
Is it because
I haven't finished healing yet?
いや コイツの力が急に伸びている》
No!
His power is suddenly growing?!
《孫 チャクラを
貸してくれってばよ！》
Son!
Lend me some of your chakra, okay?
おっしゃ～！
All right!
仙法・熔遁螺旋手裏剣！
Sage Art: Lava Style Rasen Shuriken!
ま まずい！
Th-This is bad!
輪墓！
ぐぁ～っ！
Limbo!
《なぜ 輪墓をかわした!?》
What?! He dodged... my Limbo?!
よし！
All right!
はじけろ！
Burst!
《樹が切れた!?》
The tree's been severed!
我を取り込め…。
Take me within you.
《誰だ？》
Who is that?!
神樹を…。
Take the Divine Tree...
十尾をすべて取り込め。
Ten Tails...
... everything, into you.
(我愛羅)ナルトが やったのか？
Did Naruto do it?
あそこには ガイ先生も…。
Guy Sensei is over there too!
樹が消えた…。
The tree disappeared!
ガイ先生！
Guy Sensei!
ゲキマユ先生なら大丈夫だ。
Bushier Brow Sensei
is gonna be okay!
もう 死んだりなんかしねえよ。
He's not gonna die!
ナルト君が ガイ先生を!?
Naruto, you healed him?
八門を すべて開いたはずなのに。
But I thought he had activated
all Eight Gates...
うん。 なんか いろいろ
できそうな気がするんだ。
I feel like I can
do all sorts of things...
今の俺ってば…。
the way I am right now!
《扉間 : マダラの この棒に
触れても平気とは…》
He touched Madara's rods,
but he wasn't affected...
《こやつ 死にかけている間に
何があったと…》
What happened to him
while he was dying?
(サスケ)とべるか？ 二代目。
Can you teleport, Lord Second?
(扉間)そういうことか。
I see...
ああ。 四代目のマーキングと
リンクさせておいたからな。
Yeah... Since I'm linked to
the Fourth's markings.
しかしだ 悪いが今の力で
とばせるのは １人だけだ。
But unfortunately...
At my current strength,
I can only teleport one person.
十分だ。 俺が行くだけでいい。
That's plenty.
I alone need to go.
(香燐)サスケ！
Sasuke!
《大蛇丸 : 彼の風が
また強さを…》
His wind...
has gotten even stronger.
(大蛇丸)サスケ君
あなたの風の吹きゆく先を→
Sasuke... I wanted to see where
your wind would take you...
見てみたかったけど
存分に味わえた。
But I've witnessed enough.
ここから先は→
In fact, from now on,
we'll only be a burden to you.
私たちは
足手まといにしかならないようね。
(水月)フゥ もう振り回されずに
済むかと思うと→
So we're not gonna be ordered
around anymore.
それはそれで いいけどね。
That sounds good to me too.
(重吾)サスケ。
Sasuke...
(香燐)おい！
Hey...
なに諦めようとしてんだよ
お前ら！
Why are you trying
to give up, guys?
ウチは… ウチは…。
I... I...
ゲジマユと我愛羅は
ガイ先生を守ってくれ。
Bushy Brow and Gaara,
take care of Bushier Brow Sensei.
ナルト君 ガイ先生を本当に…。
Naruto...
Thank you for... Guy Sensei...
ナルト。
Naruto...
お前が火影になったら
一緒に杯をかわそう。
When you become Hokage,
let's have a drink together.
おう！
You got it!
ナルトか!?
Is that Naruto?!
《オビト… お前…》
Obito...
You...
(オビト)ハァ… ハァ…。
(サクラ)あなたは敵。
You're an enemy.
仲間をいっぱい傷つけ 殺した。
You hurt and killed
many of my comrades...
だから 本当は
こんなこと言いたくはない。
I don't want to say this, but...
けど この１回だけは
味方として特別…。
I'm going to consider you
an ally just this once.
ナルトを助けてくれて ありがとう。
Thank you for saving Naruto.
(オビト)最後に頼みたいことがある。
I have one final favor to ask you.
味方でなくていい 敵としてだ。
Not as an ally, but as an enemy...
(マダラ)そうか 神樹そのものが。
I understand now...
The Divine Tree itself...
ハハハ… ハハハハ！
すべてを一つにする時がきた。
The time has come
for all to become one.
《大じいちゃん仙人に会って
力をもらったからかな？
Is it because
I met Super Gramps Sage
and got more power from him?
こっからでも ハッキリ感じる。
I can feel it clearly even
from here...
大じいちゃんの片方の力を》
The other half of
Super Gramps' power.
お前では 俺を倒せん。
You cannot take me down.
俺は いわば完全なる不死。
Essentially, I am completely immortal now.
永久を手にしたのだ！
I have obtained eternity!
バーカ！ 俺がお前を倒すんじゃねえ。
You idiot!
I'm not taking you down...
俺らで倒すんだってばよ！
We're gonna take you down!
お前をな マダラ。
Your time has come, Madara.
(マダラ)六道仙術を開花し→
One has awakened
the Six Paths' Senjutsu...
片や輪廻眼を開眼したか。
and the other awakened
the Rinnegan, huh?
だがな 俺は その二つの力を
両方 併せ持つ存在だ。
However... I possess
both of those powers!
これが最後の戦いだ。
This is the final battle!
(マダラ)俺の力と お前らの力…。
My powers versus yours...
どっちが上か
決着をつけてくれよう！
Let's settle who is superior,
once and for all!
《仙法・陰遁雷派！》
Sage Art:
Shadow Style Thunder Blast!
《サスケが…》
Sasuke's gone?!
《この左目… なるほど》
This left eye...
So that's what it can do...
《この距離 瞬身？
Teleportation? This distance?
いや これは移動したのではない》
No, he didn't teleport!
《よそ見すんなってばよ！》
You should pay attention!
《輪墓！》
Limbo!
《何だあれは？》
What is that?!
《まただ…》
He did it again!
《仙法・嵐遁光牙！》
Sage Art!
Gale Style: Fang of Light!
《また… くる！》
It's coming again!
そこか！
Over there!
《当たらない》
It didn't hit.
サスケ そっちへ行ったぞ！
Sasuke, it's headed your way!
何か目に見えねえのが
うろちょろしてやがる！
Something I can't see is
ambling around you.
そうか？
俺には はっきり見えてるぞ。
Oh yeah? I can see it clearly!
《コイツら… やはり 俺の輪墓を》
These guys can see my Limbo...
《これは… もう１人のマダラだ》
It's... another Madara.
(マダラ)輪廻眼となって
見えるようになったか。
So he can see it with his Rinnegan...
そして ナルト キサマは
見えはしないが 感知ができる。
And that one,
can't see it but senses it...
ナルト！ どうやら
もう１人のマダラには→
Naruto!
Looks like our physical attacks...
こちら側からの物理攻撃は
効果がないようだ。
have no effect on
the other Madara.
ああ！
Yeah!
《本来なら こちらの世界からは→
Normally, one shouldn't be able to
sense or see it from this realm...
感知することも
目視することも不可能。
見えざる世界
輪墓に存在する俺を…。
That "me" exists in
the invisible world of "Limbo."
どうやって これほどの力を
急に得たというのだ？》
How did they both obtain
such power so suddenly?
《あの うちはサスケ。
That Sasuke Uchiha...
He was the only one who
awakened the straight pattern,
ヤツは唯一 俺と同じ
直巴の写輪眼を開眼していた》
Choku-Tomoe Sharingan
just like mine.
《サスケと俺には 何か血とは違う
繋がりがあるのかもしれんな。
Perhaps Sasuke and I share
a bond that goes beyond blood.
ならば さぞや その左目も→
Well then...
That left eye should suit me perfectly!
俺の眼として
しっくりくるだろう》
え…。
《それが お前の左目の能力か》
So, that's your left eye's
ability as well.
なら 試してみろよ。
Then try it.
その程度で死にはしないよな？
That's not enough to kill you, is it?
So the Six Paths' Sage Chakra
can affect
《影のマダラにも
六道の仙人チャクラによる→
the shadow Madara too, huh?
攻撃は効くか。
あの右腕の傷。
That wound on his right arm...
最初に ナルトの攻撃を
ガードしたときに できたもの》
is from blocking
Naruto's first attack earlier.
お前の影は 一定時間で
自分に戻るようだな。
It seems your shadow
returns to your body
after a certain amount of time.
ナルト またヤツの影が出現したら
そっちは お前がやれ。
Naruto, when his shadow
emerges again, go after it.
俺は 目に見えるほうをやる。
ただし…。
I'll take on the visible one. However...
へっ お前に命令されっと
イラつくのは→
I used to hate it when
you would order me around...
今でも変わんねえみてぇだわ 俺。
Some things never change, huh?
最後まで話を聞け。
Let me finish.
いいか？ 今が チャンスだ。
This is our chance.
ヤツとヤツの影は おそらく
少しの間 重なったままだ。
Madara and his shadow
will probably stay merged
for a little while longer.
なんでもいい。
I don't care what it is,
but get a Sage Power Jutsu ready.
次も仙人の力のまま
術を準備しろ。
動きを封じる術がいい。
One that seals movement.
なら 俺様のチャクラを使え。
封印術を仕込める。
Then you should use my chakra
to build your Sealing Jutsu.
サンキュー えっと…。
守鶴だ！
Thanks... ummm...
It's Shukaku!
《輪墓の継続時間と
その発動間隔。
He's estimating the Limbo's duration,
そして それに対する
対処法を想定したか。
activation interval
and how to counter it...
なるほど 勘がいい。
冷静な分析と判断能力。
He's got a sharp intuition,
calm analyzing and
judgment skills,
そして 俺と同じ直巴。
and a Choku-Tomoe Sharingan
just like mine.
オビトより早く生まれていれば→
If he had only been born
before Obito...
コイツを…。
he would be my...
いや 今更
そんなことは どうでもいい。
No... There's no point
in reflecting now.
何があったにしろ 今のコイツらは→
No matter what's happened,
I must keep in mind that
these two aren't ordinary brats.
ただのガキではないと
理解しなければ。
すぐにでも
両目を揃えるとするか》
I need to get
my other eye back soon.
仙法・磁遁螺旋丸！
Sage Art: Magnet Style Rasengan!
俺にも六道の力が…。
And I have Six Paths Power too...
《千鳥！》
Chidori!
ナルト！ それを俺に向かって打て！
それで うまくいく！
Naruto, shoot that towards me!
I'll take care of the rest.
It's a bit irritating,
but there's no time to argue!
チラッとイラつくけど
疑う余地はねえな！
Why am I here?
《なぜ 俺が ここへ…》
ナルト！ 六道仙人から授かった術
わかっているな！
Naruto, the jutsu the Sage of
Six Paths gave you...
You know it, right?
おう！ 今が その…。
Yeah, the time is now!
What?
何だ!?
移動した！
He moved?
He substituted his shadow?
《影を身代わりにしたのか!?》
Over there!
あそこだ！
サスケ コイツは俺が止めてっから
本体を追え！
Sasuke, I'll hold this one down,
so go after the real one!
《ここまで離れると 輪廻眼の
能力は使えないようだな。
Seems like his Rinnegan
can't reach this distance.
少しだが お前の左目の能力も
わかってきたぞ サスケ》
I'm starting to understand
your left eye's abilities, Sasuke.
急げ サスケ！
Hurry, Sasuke!
マダラの先には…。
Madara is heading straight for...
カカシ先生がいる！
Kakashi Sensei!
ぐわっ！
Hurry and destroy my Rinnegan...
はやく輪廻眼を潰せ。
黒ゼツを もう止められそうにない。
I can't hold off Black Zetsu any longer.
《だが さすがに速いな サスケ》
I must admit Sasuke sure is fast.
Kamui!
《神威！》
チッ！
Damn!
Just his upper body, huh?
《上半身だけを…》
Hurry!
はやく…。
I know!
わかってる！
させん！
Oh no, you don't!
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
boku to yoku ni ta itami uchiake te kure ta hito
Hearing someone tell me about
the same kind of pain I have
futo hitori ja nain datte omoetan da
Made me think that I'm not alone
dakedo nagareta namida kamishime ta nukumori o
But the flowing tears and the warmth I relished
itsumade mo boku wa dakishimete ireru ka na?
How long can those envelop me?
kizutsui te kizutsui te nai te nai te tsuyoku nare subete
Hurting again and again,
crying over and over gives you strength for everything
me ni utsuru sono keshiki wa eien ni tada kokoro e to
That scenery you see goes straight to the heart,
massugu tsunagatte iku
now and forever
hanate niji no sora omoi nara koko ni aru (my heart)
Let it go, the rainbow sky, my wishes are here (My heart)
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
hanate niji no sora
Let it go, the rainbow sky
The Rinnegan will fall
into Madara's hands.
輝く夏！
歌のお祭りが始まりますよ！
If he ends up with both eyes,
terrible things will happen.
Terrible things?
How much worse can it get?
＜２時間スペシャル！＞
If both Rinnegan are restored
to their true owner...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Infinite Dream"
今年は
戦後70年という節目の年です。
... I fear no one will be able
to stand against him.
戦中 戦後から平成まで→
時代を超えた名曲特集！
パート１は この曲からです！